（刑事调查科）
（灵车出口 灵车专用）
干
Fuck.
不是说好五百怎么只有三百啊
He said NT$500, but there's only NT$300.
你哪里的
Who are you with?
万华 跟黑哥的
I'm with Boss Black from Wanhua.
了解
Understood.
不好意思
Sorry about that.
洪爷在道上一向有头有脸的
Boss Hung always had a good reputation.
今天大殓仪式
Today is his funeral, so of course it has to be grand.
总要办得风风光光
so of course it has to be grand.
要是有一天你们老大仙游了
If your boss kicks the bucket,
我们一样到台北给你撑场面
we'll also go to Taipei to show support.
今天就帮帮忙
Please help us out.
哪里的
Who are you with?
万华 跟黑哥的
Boss Black from Wanhua.
不好意思
Apologies.
功德无量
Appreciate it.
我们有排骨和炖肉
We have pork chop and soy-stewed pork.
都很好吃的
They are both really good.
你也是跟黑哥的喔
You're with Boss Black too?
今天来多少人
How many people came today?
没有一千 也有八百
If not a thousand, at least 800.
很久没有看过这种大场面
Haven't been to such a big event in a while.
洪爷果然够派头
Boss Hung sure loved extravagance.
那个疯子 真的从台北过来把他干掉了
That lunatic really came up from Taipei to whack him.
你说谁
Who?
一个叫做桂林仔的人
They call him the "Kuilin Kid".
什么桂林仔
Kuilin Kid?
靠 我跟你说
I'm telling you.
虽然他是个疯子
He might be a lunatic,
但我真的觉得他挺猛的
but I think he's pretty awesome.
你认识他
You know him?
桂林仔 是中山区顶厝庄 任因九的细汉
The Kuilin Kid is a young gun from the streets of Zhongshan District.
两个月前
Two months ago,
九哥到洪爷的赌场赢了八百多万
Brother Nine won NT$8 million at Boss Hung's casino.
洪爷不认账
Boss Hung wouldn't pay up,
九哥一怒之下 叫桂林仔去收债
so Brother Nine told Kuilin Kid to go collect the debt.
你知道结果怎么样
You know what happened?
结果怎么样
What happened?
结果
Turns out,
桂林仔拿着手榴弹
Kuilin Kid brought a grenade.
手榴弹喔
A grenade!
到了那边
Once he got there,
拿了八百万之后
and collected the NT$8 million,
炸爆整个赌场
he blew up the casino.
干掉洪爷 你说他屌不屌
Killed Boss Hung. Isn't he cool?
-屌 -屌吼
- Cool. - Right?
但是枪打出头鸟了
But he may have shot himself in the foot.
铁头哥下了追杀令之后
Now that Ironhead has issued a kill order,
看来桂林仔是凶多吉少
it looks like the odds are against Kuilin Kid.
喂 奶奶
Hi, grandma.
怎么了
What is it?
寄给你的钱收到没有
Did you get the money I sent you?
哪有多
It's not too much.
几万块而已啊
Just a few grand.
好啦
Okay.
我这一阵子不在喔
I will be away for a while.
要出国工作
Going overseas for work.
-你自己饭要记得吃 -铁头哥来了
- Remember to eat. - Ironhead is here!
先这样 不跟你讲了
I'll talk to you later.
铁头哥好
Ironhead!
铁头哥来了
Ironhead is here.
我叫金毛
My name is Goldie.
等等一起回台北
Let's go back to Taipei together.
我叫陈桂林
I'm Chen Kui-lin.
我有名有姓
I have a real name.
以后不要再叫什么桂林仔
Stop calling me Kuilin Kid.
铁头
Ironhead
-过去 -好
- Go. - Okay.
-还好吗 -没事
- Are you okay? - I'm fine.
（四年后）
好
Okay...
我马上过来 好
I'll be over shortly. Okay.
还有多久时间
How much time left?
顶多半年
Half a year at most.
快的话
Worst case scenario,
三个月
three months.
艾瑞莎或得舒缓 行不行
Will Iressa or Tarceva help?
现在用太晚了
It's too late.
妥复克 新的药
What about the new drug, Giotrif?
你们医院有没有
Does your hospital have that?
你看这肺 都化白了
Look at this lung. It's all white.
恐怕也来不及
It's probably too late.
换肺呢
Lung transplant?
贵卿
Kuei-ching.
你也是个医生
You're a doctor too.
这样的情况 你应该很清楚
You should know what the situation is.
你奶奶出事了 赶快过来一下
Your grandma is in trouble. Get here quickly.
张小姐 怎么现在才来
Ms. Chang, what took you so long?
医生等你好久了
The doctor's been waiting for you.
你是她谁
What's your relationship to the patient?
我是她医生
I'm her doctor.
你是她医生
You're her doctor?
她卵巢里面
She has an 18cm tumor
长了一颗18公分的肿瘤
inside her ovary.
你知道吗
Did you know that?
刚刚照了CT扫描
She just had a CT scan.
她整个腹腔胀得很严重
Her abdominal cavity is severely bloated.
现在必须开刀
She needs surgery right now.
手术要签同意书
I need a signed consent form.
养老院那边的人不愿意签
The nursing home won't do it.
你是她联络簿上唯一可以联络到的人
You're the only contact we could to get in touch with.
所以要求你来签字
So please sign the form.
还是她有其他亲人
Or does she have other relatives?
赶快做决定吧
Make a decision now.
如果手术中
If her life is in danger
奶奶有生命危险
during surgery,
抢不抢救
do we resuscitate?
插不插管
Do we intubate?
我们就按照正常手术程序
We'll follow regular surgery procedures.
必要时
If necessary, we will resuscitate.
会尽力抢救
we will resuscitate.
不要插管
No intubation.
医生
Doctor.
拜托不要插管
Please, no intubation.
（手术中）
这种手术成功率有多大
What are the chances of success?
你是希望她手术成功还是不成功
Do you want her surgery to be successful?
如果手术成功你能回来照顾她吗
If it is, will you be able to take care of her?
她最多就是住几天医院
After a few days in hospital,
最后还是要回到养老院
she still has to return to the nursing home.
放学啦
You finished school?
妈妈还在工作
Mommy is still working.
你跟爸爸先吃
You eat with Daddy first.
怎么样
How did it go?
发生车祸的是一辆载满鸡蛋的货车
The accident was between a truck full of eggs
以及一台运钞车
and a cash transport vehicle.
两台车相撞之后
After the collision,
鸡蛋散布满地
eggs covered the ground
而千元大钞全飞散出来
as NT$1,000 bills scattered everywhere.
警方也呼吁这些在现场的民众
Police are urging residents
主动将捡拾到的钞票
who took the bills to return them
尽快归还到邻近的派出所
to their nearest police station as soon as possible,
同时也强调 如果将钞票占为己有
emphasizing that keeping the cash
可能会触犯侵占遗失物的罪行
constitutes misappropriation of lost property.
请民众主动自首投案 切勿以身试法
Residents are advised to turn themselves in and not test the law.
以上是本台记者…
According to reporters...
这些年
The money
你托我给奶奶的钱
you told me to give Grandma over the years
她都没用过
has never been used.
去年生日买了一只手表
Except for this watch she bought last birthday.
三百块
NT$300.
没想到我最后一次见她
I can't believe the last time I saw her
是四年前
was four years ago.
所以你这样躲来躲去
How long do you plan to
要躲到什么时候呢
keep running and hiding?
我本来一直很担心的
I had been really worried.
担心有一天被抓 上了新闻
Worried that seeing news of my capture
我奶奶看到会很难过
would break Grandma's heart.
现在她走了
But now that she's gone,
我要干一票大的
I'm going to do something big,
让道上的所有人都知道我是谁
so every criminal in the underworld will know who I am.
有一件事情
There's something.
我不知道是不是应该现在告诉你
I'm not sure if I should tell you now.
报告出来了
The report is out.
你要有心理准备
You need to be mentally prepared.
什么意思啊
What does that mean?
（胸片）
第四期
Stage 4.
肺癌
Lung cancer.
末期
Terminal.
你确定
Are you sure?
有没有药啊
Any treatments?
换肺呢
Lung transplant?
来不及
It's too late.
还有多久啊
How long do I have?
顶多半年
Six months at most.
快的话三个月
Worst case scenario, three months.
不要再抽了
Stop smoking.
抽死一个少一个
What difference does it make?
你知道吗
Don't you know?
肺癌临终前是很痛苦的
Lung cancer gets very agonizing towards the end.
与其像一只死在暗角的老鼠
Rather than dying like a street rat,
倒不如光明正大一点
you could act more honorably.
人死留名
Do what's right.
至少换来一点尊严
At least die with a little dignity.
你要我去自首
You want me to turn myself in?
赶紧帮我找个肺
Go find me another lung.
不好意思 张小姐
Excuse me, Ms. Chang.
你们要干嘛
What do you want?
吉祥养老院今天有一位侯姓奶奶去世
Granny Hou from Lucky Nursing Home passed away today.
你认识
Did you know her?
你们是谁啊
Who are you?
（刑事警察）
她有个孙子
She had a grandson,
叫陈桂林
Chen Kui-lin.
你认识
Do you know him?
没听说过
Never heard of him.
Never heard of him?
奶奶的联络人名册有你的名字
You were in her contact book.
你是她谁
What's your relationship with her?
我就是个卖药的
I'm just a pharmacist.
有时候把药送去养老院
I sometimes deliver medicine to nursing homes
然后顺便帮老人家检查身体
and check the residents' health while I'm there.
任何人都可以有我的联络电话
Anyone could have my number.
有陈桂林的消息通知我
Let me know if you hear from Chen Kui-lin.
（台北市中城第一分局 分队长 陈灰）
关圣帝君在上
Dear Holy Emperor Guan.
弟子陈桂林在下
This is your worshipper Chen Kui-lin.
若是帝君要弟子桂林前去自首
If Emperor Guan would like me to surrender,
请帝君明示
please give me a sign.
帮我把钱放进去 然后准备好你的身份证
Put the money in and get your ID ready.
快了
Won't be long.
东西先帮我准备好
Get everything ready.
-今天来的比较多 -袋子再帮我把钱放进去
- Lots of people today. - Put them in the bag.
先生
Sir.
不要挡在门口啊
Please don't block the door.
先生
Sir.
我陈桂林
I'm Chen Kui-lin.
陈先生
Mr. Chen.
要自首的话 我们准备好身份证
If you're turning yourself in,
到那边去排队啊
get your ID ready and go over there.
我来自首
I'm turning myself in.
来这里谁不是要自首啊
You and everyone else.
自首要守规矩
There are procedures.
不要挡在门口
Don't block the door.
往那边引导
Follow instructions.
快去那边 赶快
Go over there. Hurry.
到那边排队
Go line up.
-到那边再准备你的证件 -都往那边走
- Get your ID ready. - Go this way.
去里面 不要进来
Go inside. Don't come in.
都往那边
Everyone, this way.
走啦 里面
Come on. Inside.
不要那么凶嘛 大家都赶时间
Easy. We're all in a hurry.
排队赶快走
Quickly get in line.
（全台三大通缉犯）
（通缉犯一号 林禄和“牛头”）
（通缉犯二号 许伟强”香港仔”）
（通缉犯三号 陈桂林）
不要这样跑 慢一点
Don't run. Slow down.
佑佑
Yu-yu.
他们才说怎么没有看到你们呢
They were just saying they didn't see you.
-你们在这里啊 -佑佑妈妈
- But you're here. - Yu-yu's mom.
球给我
Give me the ball.
来
Come...
他就说肚子饿
He says he's hungry.
这里有三明治啊
We have sandwiches here.
来 这里
Here.
-我买给大家吃 -不用 我去买
- I bought lots. - It's okay, I'll go buy one.
我去买
I'll go buy one.
你想干嘛
What do you want?
有家庭真好
It's nice to have a family.
你儿子多大了
How old is your son?
你要说什么
Tell me what you want.
你认识香港仔吗
Do you know Hongkie?
什么香港仔
What Hongkie?
二十多年前 猎狐行动
Operation Fox Hunt over 20 years ago.
信义区吴兴街公寓跟警察火拼
Standoff with police at Xinyi's Wuxing St. apartments.
听说用光了信义分局所有弹药
I heard Xinyi Police Department used up all their ammo.
他当年中了很多枪
He was shot multiple times.
你肯定帮过他
You must have helped him.
你要干嘛
What are you doing?
他在哪
Where is he?
我有事找他
I need to speak to him.
你知不知道 你为什么现在 还可以站在这里跟我讲话
Do you know why you can stand here and talk to me right now?
要是我会说 你早就在监狱了
If I were a snitch, you'd already be in prison.
一定很好喝好不好
Must be a good drink.
白痴喔
You idiot.
喝喝看吧
Give it a try.
台南有个神医
There's a miracle doctor in Tainan.
不然我们明天去看一下
I'll take you to see him tomorrow.
我不是怕死啊
I'm not afraid of death.
我是怕死了都没人记得
I'm afraid of being forgotten after death.
明天帮我一个忙
Can you do me a favor tomorrow?
你做了什么
What did you do?
你把我儿子怎么了
What did you do to my son?
前两天我经过警局
The other day, I passed the police station.
我突然想到你说的
I suddenly remembered what you said.
与其像老鼠一样活着
Rather than living like a rat,
倒不如有尊严地去自首
I should turn myself in with dignity.
所以我去了
So I went.
去了以后我才知道
But it was then that I realized
原来我连自首的资格都没有
I'm not even qualified to turn myself in.
原来我还不够有价值
Turns out I don't have enough value yet.
这就是我的价值
This is my value.
周处除三害的故事你听过吗
You know the story of Zhou Chu and the Three Scourges?
大家只记得周处
People only remember Zhou Chu,
没有人会记得
but never the two other monsters
被周处杀掉那两个是谁
Zhou Chu killed.
所以周处才是那个有价值的人
That's why only Zhou Chu has value,
大家也才会记得他
and why people remember him.
我是一个快死的人了
I'm a dying man.
帮我最后一次
Help me one last time.
他到底在哪
Where is he?
我第一次见到香港仔
The first time I met Hongkie
已经是二十年前的事了
was over 20 years ago.
当天正是吴兴街枪战事件
It was the day of the Wuxing St. shootout.
晚上十点
At 10:00 p.m.,
几个小弟抬着他冲了进来
a few underlings carried him in,
要我帮他抢救
asking me to save him.
其中一颗子弹就打进了他的脑袋里
One bullet was lodged in his head.
当时我手边没有做手术的仪器
I didn't have any surgery equipment with me.
就算有我也不敢动手
I wouldn't dare operate even if I did.
结果那颗子弹
That bullet is still
就永远留在香港仔的脑袋里了
stuck in Hongkie's head.
之后他几乎每天头痛
He has headaches almost every day.
我只能帮他配一些止痛药
I can only prescribe him some painkillers,
让他每个月派人来拿
which someone fetches for him every month.
是谁帮他拿药
Who fetches his medicine?
好
Okay.
好 我知道了
Okay, I understand.
从十年前开始
For about 10 years now,
就有一个叫小美的女生来帮他拿药
a girl named Hsiao-mei has been getting his medicine.
那时候她才十几岁
She was only a teenager back then.
她是什么背景我都不知道
I know nothing about her background.
叫小美
Her name is Hsiao-mei?
程小美
Cheng Hsiao-mei.
我帮你拍张照
Let me take a photo.
一 二 三 耶
One, two, three, yeah.
你儿子这么喜欢吃冰
Your son sure loves ice cream.
对牙齿应该不好
It's not good for his teeth.
你绑架人还担心他牙齿好不好啊
You kidnapped him and you're worried about his teeth?
林禄和呢
Where's Lin Lu-ho?
这个人消失很久了
He disappeared a long time ago.
十几年前 从我这里寄了一封信给他妈妈
Over a decade ago, he sent a letter from here to his mom.
这是他妈妈的回信
This is her reply.
（高雄市老人长期照顾中心 杨淑珍）
（一失足成千古恨 再回头已百年身）
（舍弃贪 嗔 痴 来生再做新的人）
我知道的都已经告诉你了
I've told you everything I know.
我儿子在哪
Where's my son?
见到程小美我就会告诉你
I'll tell you once I see Cheng Hsiao-mei.
妈
Mom!
妈 好重喔
Mom, it's so heavy!
你有没有怎样我看一下
Are you hurt? Let me take a look.
没有
No.
要住房吗
Would you like a room?
有房间吗
Any vacancies?
一晚八百五
NT$850 a night.
听我说 下次别再找老鼠明
Don't get it from Rat Ming next time.
但他的货质量好
But his stuff is so cheap.
你的手怎么了
What happened to your hand?
没事
Nothing.
那个老鼠明
That Rat Ming
跟他拿些货 跟我算钱
was trying to haggle over every cent,
捅了他几下
so I stabbed him a few times.
你要不要我帮你擦药
Want me to put on some ointment?
没事 小问题
I'm fine. No big deal.
不然我帮你拿头痛药
You want your headache pills?
不用
No need.
把这洗干净
Clean this up.
怎样 有什么吃
So? Anything to eat?
猪血糕 鸭血 还有棺材板
Pig blood cake,duck blood, deep-fried sandwich.
靠 又猪血又鸭血 还嫌不够多血吗
Shit.Pig blood and duck blood again.Don't you still think there's enough blood?
抽支烟
Let's go for a smoke.
你刚才笑什么
What were you laughing at?
没有 老大
Nothing, boss.
我问你刚才笑什么
I asked you what were you laughing at.
对不起 老大
Sorry, boss.
你想到了什么笑成这样
Something must have made you laugh.
你说个原因出来 可能我会明白
If you give me a reason, maybe I'll understand.
但你现在不说我就觉得很受伤
But not saying anything really hurts me.
证明你
It means
心里想着些脏东西 连说都不敢说
you have dirty thoughts you don't dare to say.
喝了多少瓶
How many bottles have we had?
六瓶
Six.
那喝完这杯就七瓶了
Finish this to make it seven.
拿给我
Give it to me.
没事
Enough.
关门
Close up.
你赶快去把脸擦一擦 快点
Go clean up your face. Hurry.
吃什么
What are you eating?
今天我托人送了些东西给你妈妈
I got some stuff delivered to your mom today.
现在监狱的规矩真麻烦
Prison rules are so annoying these days.
汤 冷冻食品
Soup, frozen foods,
猪血 鸭血都不能送
pig blood and duck blood are all banned.
连椰子和百香果都不行
Even coconut and passionfruit.
椰子不行我明白
Coconut I understand.
打在头上真的会死人
You can kill someone with that.
但百香果不行真的很奇怪
But banning passionfruit makes no sense.
百香果怎么杀人呢
How can you kill someone with a passionfruit?
呛死吗
Choke them to death?
你放心
Don't worry.
我会托人在里面 把你妈妈照顾好
I'll get my people on the inside to look after your mom.
队长
Captain.
这是张贵卿的通话记录
Chang Kuei-ching's call records.
大部分都是跟她老公的通话记录
They're mostly calls to her husband,
但是这两天有出现另外两个号码
but two other numbers popped up recently.
其中一个是便利商店买的电话卡
One is a SIM bought from a convenience store.
另外一个是台中的店家
The other is a shop in Taichung.
台中店家 什么店啊
What kind of shop?
是一间发廊
A hair salon.
小美发廊
Hsiao-Mei's Hair Salon.
而在中南部地区阳光露脸
The sun is out in south-central Taiwan.
中午的温度在中南部的朋友
People in these areas,
可以明显感觉到中午就热了起来
will start feeling the heat around noon
到了30到31度的高温
when temperatures reach 30-31 degrees.
中部地区日夜温差相对会比较明显
It will get much colder at night in central regions.
南部地区温差仍然是偏大
In the south, the temperature gap remains large.
不过明天南高屏的温度
But tomorrow's temperatures...
不好意思
Excuse me.
是来剪头发的吗
Are you here for a haircut?
不然你先进去好了
Please go inside first.
你今天想要剪头发还是修胡子
Do you want a cut or a shave?
修胡子
Shave.
你想要修一点还是全部刮掉
Just a trim or shave everything off?
没关系 我们先修一点
It's okay. Let's trim a little bit,
你不喜欢的话 我们再刮掉
and you can decide from there.
好
Okay.
等一下喔
Please wait.
你看起来不像台中人
You don't look like you're from Taichung.
来找朋友
I'm here to see friends.
你这胡子很久没刮了吗
When was the last time you shaved?
一两天吧
A couple of days ago.
那你的生长激素很厉害耶
Your growth hormones are impressive.
今天先这样吧
That'll do for today.
谢谢
Thanks.
跟你说过多少遍
How many times do I have to tell you?
修胡子 两边要对齐
The two sides need to be even.
先生
Sir.
听得懂广东话吗
Do you understand Cantonese?
一点点
A little.
我帮你修一下好吗
How about I fix it for you?
好
Sure.
你上去帮我拿酒
Go upstairs and fetch my liquor.
平常很少人只修胡子
Not many come in for just a beard trim.
你挺特别的
You're quite unusual.
约了朋友在这边碰
I've got a friendly catch-up,
所以想修一修
so I thought I'd get a trim.
朋友在这边开店吗
Your friend owns a store around here?
没有
No.
只是约在这边
We're just meeting here
吃个饭
to have a meal.
男的
Is it a guy
还是女的呢
or a girl?
男女都有
Both.
中学同学
Junior high classmates.
所以 今晚就留在这里
So you're staying here tonight?
如果太晚的话明天再回去
If it gets too late tonight, I'll head back tomorrow.
有地方住吗
Got a place to stay?
在这里应该不难找吧
Shouldn't be too hard to find one.
你今天才到吗
You just arrived today?
什么意思
What was that?
你今天才到吗
You just arrived today?
是啊
Yeah.
但 为什么
But how come
我好像昨晚已经见过你
I feel like I saw you last night?
有吗
Really?
你不就住在对面精明新宿旅馆吗
Weren't you staying at the hotel across the road?
你已经偷看了我整晚了
You were spying on me all night,
还在装
yet you still pretend?
大哥
Mister.
你认错人了吧
You got the wrong person.
你是不是来找小美的
Did you come to see Hsiao-mei?
你是她谁呀
Who are you to her?
外面那台车谁的
Who owns the car outside?
麻烦移一下车
Please move it.
现在是怎样
What's going on?
有民众投诉说有人乱停车
There's a car blocking the street.
-赶快把车开走 -会啦 不用担心
- Move it now. - I will, don't worry.
我们就停一下下而已
We just stopped for a minute.
不好意思
Sorry...
你们赶快把车移走 快点
Move the car, quickly.
-在动 没看到吗  -等你们啊
- I'm moving, can't you see? - Hurry up.
他妈的 你走去哪
What the fuck are you doing?
我去买烟啦
Buying cigarettes.
快一点
Hurry up.
开车了
Drive.
你不要再过来了
Don't come again.
今天来刮胡子那人你认识
Do you know that guy who came in today?
不认识
No.
那个人
That guy
挂羊头卖狗肉
was not who he said he was.
以为他 找朋友
Meeting with friends?
他妈的 想找碴
He was looking for trouble.
是喔
Really?
我想好了
I've decided.
干老鼠明一票
I'm going after Rat Ming.
顺便拿走他的货
Steal his product while I'm at it,
然后躲一阵子
then go into hiding for a while.
去金门
In Kinmen.
为什么
Why?
不是说过很多遍
I've said it many times.
一个地方不可以留太久
You can't stay in one place for too long.
还有那个警察
Besides, the cops will
早晚会认出我
recognize me sooner or later.
有什么放不下吗
Is there a reason you want to stay?
没有
No.
下次能不能吃火锅
Let's have hotpot next time.
来 喝吧
Let's drink.
那么快
That was quick.
老板
Shopkeeper.
买单
Check.
等一下
- Wait... - Fuck.
老板 买单
Shopkeeper, check.
等一下
Wait...
搞什么东西
What's going on?
还以为老大那么快
I thought Boss was done.
别跑
Stop!
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
我叫陈桂林
Chen Kui-lin.
我认识你吗
Do I know you?
给我一个理由
Tell me why.
-你要离开 还是留下 -离开
- You want to stay or go? - Go.
如果警察找上你
If the cops come for you,
你就说香港仔是我杀的
tell them I killed Hongkie.
为什么
Why?
我要让所有人都知道香港仔是我杀的
I want everyone to know I killed Hongkie.
为什么
Why?
你还有亲人吗
Do you have any other family?
香港仔是我唯一的亲人
Hongkie was my only family.
你们结婚了
You married him?
我妈嫁给他了
My mom married him.
她在替香港仔服刑
She's serving time for Hongkie.
二级贩毒
Second-degree drug trafficking.
被判15年
罚金一千五百万
NT$15 million fine.
这是我这辈子都还不了的债
It's a debt I'll never be able to repay.
为什么
Why?
因为她想要让全世界的人都知道
Because she wants the whole world to know
那毒是她卖的
she trafficked those drugs.
为什么
Why?
因为香港仔
Because Hongkie
把她从另外一个男人手中救出来
rescued her from another man.
我们现在要去哪
Where are we going now?
这台车子留给你
You can keep this car.
我们还会再见面吗
Will we meet again?
从现在开始你自由了
You're free now.
保重
Take care.
台中精明商圈小美发廊 以及距离几步之遥的牛肉面店
There was an execution-style shooting at Taichung's Hsiao-Mei Hair Salon
竟然发生行刑式枪击
and a nearby beef noodle soup shop,
造成一共三名男子死亡
resulting in the deaths of three men.
而在不远处的废弃温室中
An additional shooting victim was found
也发现一名同样遭到枪击的死者
not far away in an abandoned greenhouse.
警方不排除为同一人犯案
Police believe the killings may be related.
警方调查发现
Investigations have revealed that
其中一名死者竟然是绰号
one of the deceased is
香港仔的十大枪击要犯
the notorious fugitive nicknamed Hongkie.
并且有一名少女遭到狭持
A young woman was also kidnapped during the incident,
据了解 这名少女已经在 今天清晨顺利脱逃
but managed to escape early this morning.
根据脱逃的程姓女子爆料
According to the woman, surnamed Cheng,
犯案凶嫌也是一名通缉犯
the murder suspect is also a fugitive
名字叫做陈桂林
by the name of Chen Kui-lin.
四年前他犯下了枪击案之后
Four years ago, he committed a fatal shooting
就消失无踪了
before disappearing.
如今再度地出现
Could his reappearance
背后是否有更大的黑帮勾结呢
indicate a bigger gang conspiracy behind the scenes?
警方已经扩大调阅监视器
Police are reviewing surveillance footage
追缉嫌犯
and pursuing the suspect.
到案说明
and provided an account of the apprehension.
请问杨淑珍在不在
Excuse me, is Yang Shu-chen here?
什么谁
What? Who?
这
Her.
（张贵卿小姐）
杨淑珍
Yang Shu-chen
都走了三年了
died three years ago.
这火化的钱
The cost of her cremation
都还是政府垫付的
had to be paid by the government.
这些啊 是她财物
These were her belongings.
你点收一下
Please check them.
《（新心灵舍）》
（一失足成千古恨）
（再回头已百年身）
（舍弃贪 嗔 痴）
（来生再做新的人）
（澎湖县湖西乡澎14乡道）
这是白粥
This is plain congee,
青菜 豆腐 还有笋丝
vegetables, tofu, and bamboo shoots.
慢慢吃
Enjoy.
今天早上
This morning,
我和两个师兄弟到菜市场买菜
I went shopping at the markets with two brothers,
遇到一个婆婆
where we met an old lady.
婆婆她问我
She asked me,
为什么她觉得忙碌了大半生
why does she feel like she's toiled her entire life,
还是一无所有
yet still has nothing?
我问她
I asked her,
一无所有不好吗
what's wrong with having nothing?
你们说呢
What do you think?
能够没有目的地活着 不好吗
Isn't it good to live without a purpose?
目的是人脑想出来的
Purpose is invented by man,
必然是关于世俗之物
so it must surely relate to worldly things.
一昧地追求世俗的向往
Blindly pursuing worldly desires
这是愚昧的事情
is a foolish thing.
贪
Greed,
嗔
anger,
痴
and delusion
是所有烦恼的根源
are the roots of all suffering.
这些都是浪费生命的毒害
These are all life-wasting poisons.
所以回过头来
So, looking back,
也许生命的意义
perhaps the meaning of life
是它根本没意义
is to have no meaning at all.
♪ 曾经 我茫然前行 ♪
♪ I once wandered aimlessly ♪
♪ 黯夜的路上 ♪
♪ On the dark night road ♪
♪ 微风 刺痛着灵魂 ♪
♪ The gentle breeze pricks my soul ♪
♪ 找不到应该的方向 ♪
♪ Unable to find the right direction ♪
♪ 生命这样的旅程 ♪
♪ The journey of life ♪
♪ 要用多少的泪水来完整 ♪
♪ Requires how many tears to complete? ♪
♪ 是否我能期待遥远天际 ♪
♪ Do I have a horizon to look forward to? ♪
尊者好
Your Holiness,
终于看到你了 好高兴
I finally got to see you. I'm so happy.
谢谢尊者对我们的帮助
Thank you so much.
谢谢
- Thank you. Thank you. - Thank you.
尊者
Your Holiness.
尊者谢谢你
Your Holiness, thank you.
真的非常感谢你
Thank you so much.
尊者谢谢你
Your Holiness, thank you.
♪ 我渴求你的微笑来完整 ♪
♪ Is completed by my yearning and your smile ♪
♪ 你能为我打开自由的门 ♪
♪ You can open my door to freedom ♪
这种药
This kind of medicine
通常是治疗肺癌用的
is used for treating lung cancer.
尊者
Your Holiness.
你醒了
You're awake.
感觉怎么样
How do you feel?
你刚才腹吐黑水
You just vomited black water.
知道吗
Did you know that?
身体里有不干净的东西
There's something unclean inside you.
什么不干净
What's unclean?
有些事你是可以理解的
There are some things you can comprehend,
有些你听了也不会明白
and others you will never understand.
不过 你放心
But don't worry.
好好休息
Get some rest.
一切都会好起来的
Everything will get better.
明天六点早课
There's a class at 6:00 a.m. tomorrow.
有精神的话来参加
Come if you have the energy.
（全台三大通辑犯）
（礼堂）
我曾经是一个子宫颈癌末期的患者
I was once a terminal cervical cancer patient.
那时候每天都像是在倒数一样
Every day felt like a countdown.
我不知道死神
I never knew when death
什么时候会来把我带走
would come for me.
我非常感谢尊者
I'm very thankful to His Holiness...
感谢他为我开悟
for enlightening me.
他的开悟
His enlightenment
胜过了无数次的手术
is more effective than any surgery.
是他
Because of him,
让我成为了一个新造的人
I have become a brand new person.
现在的我
Right now,
非常的健康
I am very healthy,
不需要任何的药物
without need for any medication
也不需要接受任何的治疗
or any treatment.
希望尊者能够再度为我开悟
I hope Your Holiness can enlighten me again
赐给我一个孩子
and bestow a child upon me.
我们都忘记了
We have all forgotten
自己才是最好的医生
that we are our best doctor.
世界上所有的药
All the medicine in the world
都比不上你自己的觉悟
cannot compare to your own enlightenment.
♪ 曾经 我茫然前行 ♪
♪ I once wandered aimlessly ♪
放下身外之物
Only by letting go of attachments
才能成为全新的人
can one become a brand new person.
♪ 微风 刺痛着灵魂 ♪
♪ The gentle breeze pricks my soul ♪
♪ 找不到应该的方向 ♪
♪ Unable to find the right direction ♪
尊者
Your Holiness.
精气神都好很多
You seem much better.
有救有救
There's still hope for you.
来 坐
Come, sit.
这本书送你
This book is for you.
有时间的时候读一下
Read it in your spare time.
《（新心灵舍）》
这书谁写的
Who wrote it?
我写的
I did.
原来是你写的
So you wrote it?
字是我写的
I wrote the words,
但是悟到道理的人不是我
though the one who inspired them is not me,
是另有其人
but someone else.
你为什么会来到这里
Why did you come here?
我想找一个人
I'm looking for someone.
找人
Who?
他叫林禄和
His name is Lin Lu-ho.
你是警察
You're a cop?
我不是警察
I'm not a cop.
那就是道上兄弟
Then you must be a gangster.
有人托我把东西交给他
I was entrusted to give something to him.
我得自己把东西给他
I must hand it to him myself.
这就是你要找的人
This is who you're looking for.
也许他不希望人家记得他
Perhaps he doesn't want to be remembered.
他什么时候死的
When did he die?
很久以前了
A long time ago.
当时他好像是被通缉
I think he was a fugitive at the time.
一直跑路
Constantly on the run.
最后跑到了澎湖
He ended up in Penghu.
那时候我是小岛医院里的医生
I was a doctor on the island back then.
深夜两点接到电话
I received a call at 2:00 a.m.
说有个伤患冲进急诊室
telling me there's a patient in the ER,
满身是血
covered in blood,
要我过去看一下
and they asked me to come in.
先生 你怎么了
Sir. What happened?
不用救我
Don't save me.
我是个罪人
I'm a sinner.
不该得到救赎
I don't deserve salvation.
这是上天的安排
It was God's plan
让我在这里碰到几位
for me to meet you all here.
我今晚
Tonight,
就葬在这里
I shall be buried here.
我看见了我的坟墓
I saw my grave,
也看见了你们的坟墓
and I also saw your graves.
我看到了宇宙诞生的那一刻
I saw the moment the universe was born.
我看到了我的一生
I saw my life,
也看到了你们的一生
and I also saw your lives.
他知道我们每个人的姓名
He knew all of our names,
出生地点
where we were born,
能活到几岁
and at what age we will die.
他是特异的人
He was an extraordinary person.
最后
In the end,
他吩咐我们在湖西乡找一个地点
he instructed us to find a spot in Huxi Township
开设一所新心灵社
and establish the New Spiritual Society,
让众生免于痛苦
to free all sentient beings from suffering.
也许
Perhaps,
你和林禄和有什么前世恩怨
you hold some grudge against Lin Lu-ho.
但是如果你不抛开执着
But if you don't let go of your attachments,
你的死期也将近
your death will be near.
我会死在这
Will I die here?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不能帮助你永生
I can't make you live forever.
只能帮你治病
I can only treat your illness.
人的死
A person's death
都是咎由自取的
is always the result of their own actions.
待会我说一句
Every time I say a line,
你跟着我说一句
you repeat after me.
我感谢天地
I thank heaven and earth.
I thank heaven and earth!
我感谢父母
I thank my parents.
I thank my parents!
我是罪人
I'm a sinner.
I'm a sinner!
我危害人间
I have harmed the world.
I have harmed the world!
我辜负苍生
I let the world down.
I let the world down!
我愿抛开一切
I'm willing to abandon everything.
I'm willing to abandon everything!
消除名利权力
Forgo fame, fortune, and power.
Forgo fame, fortune, and power!
舍弃金钱物质
Give up money and material possessions.
Give up money and material possessions!
归于真我
Return to my true self.
Return to my true self!
我先过去
I'm heading over.
上次你说要亲手交给林禄和的东西
You said you had to give something to Lin Lu-ho.
是什么
What is it?
他妈妈的骨灰
His mother's ashes.
你认识他母亲
You knew his mother?
你说你是末期肺癌
You said you have terminal lung cancer?
对
Yes.
第四期
Stage 4.
可是按目前来看
But from what I can see,
没有你说的那么严重
it's not as serious as you say.
按照这个X光片来看的话
Based on this X-ray,
我是没有办法断定是第四期
I can't confirm that you are stage 4.
你看这个阴影的部分
This shadow here
这有可能是癌细胞
could be cancer cells,
不过还要抽取细胞化验会比较准确
but a biopsy would give us more certainty.
然后还有这些白白的
There's also these white parts.
有钙化的迹象
Signs of calcification.
这个
This is
是正在康复的组织
recovering tissue.
如果你说
If you say
你之前是癌症第四期
you had stage 4 cancer before,
那代表你的癌细胞正在自我消灭
that means your cancer cells are self-destructing.
你怎么把我光片给撕了你
How could you... rip up my X-ray?
你把它撕破了
You ripped it.
那能说他这样会好起来吗
Does that mean he'll recover?
这个
That's...
很难讲啊
hard to say.
像这种奇迹
Such miracles
不是不可能
aren't impossible.
但万中无一
But it's very rare.
我看
I think
你还是要多观察一段时间
we need to observe for a little longer
我们才能下结论
before reaching any conclusions.
尊者
Your Holiness.
这个我特别帮你做的
I made this especially for you.
请坐
Please sit.
这是林禄和母亲的骨灰
This is Lin Lu-ho's mother's ashes.
这个是我带来的钱
This is the money I brought with me.
这里有多少钱
How much money is in here?
一百万
NT$1 million.
放进去
Put it inside.
银行还有存款吗
Any money in bank accounts?
都在这
It's all here.
手表也放进去
Put your watch in there too.
这个不行
Not this.
这个是我奶奶留给我的
My grandma left me this.
我知道抛开世俗之物不是件容易的事
I know it's not easy letting go of worldly possessions.
如果你现在还会犹豫
If you are still hesitant,
那表示时机还没到
it means the timing is not right.
没关系
That's okay,
你可以都拿回去
you can take it all back.
饭菜端出去
Serve the food,
然后这盘给小胖
and give this to Pao.
好 知道
Okay.
是不是有小朋友一个人啊
Did you come here by yourself?
没有 我跟妈妈来
No, I came with my mom.
-你肚子饿吗 -饿
- Are you hungry? - Yes.
-给你 -谢谢
- This is yours. - Thank you.
不客气
Welcome.
师姐
Senior sister.
我再帮你拿一份饭菜
I'll get another serving for you.
不用 我斋戒中
No need, I'm fasting.
-好 -谢谢
- Okay. - Thanks.
那你如果还饿再告诉我
Let me know if you're hungry.
好 谢谢
Okay, thank you.
拜拜
Bye.
你们有想过死了以后会去哪里吗
Where do you think you'll go when you die?
天堂
Heaven.
你怎么知道你是去天堂
How do you know you'll go to heaven?
因为我乖没有做坏事情
Because I'm good and don't do bad things.
你有伤害过小动物吗
Do you often hurt small animals?
没有 我最爱小动物了
No, I love small animals.
你有吃虾子吗
Do you eat shrimp?
有
Yes.
-鱼呢 -也有
- Fish? - Yes.
虾子比鱼好吃
Shrimp tastes better than fish.
小宝
Pao!
小宝你怎么了
Pao, are you all right?
小宝 怎么会这样
Pao, what's happening to you?
-我看看 -怎么会这样
- Let me have a look. - What's happening?
小宝
Pao...
-要不要去医院 -妈妈你先冷静
Should we take him to the hospital? Ma'am, please calm down.
-怎么会这样 -来让尊者看看
Let His Holiness take a look.
-要不要去医院 -让他脸这样 让他躺一下
- Get him to the hospital. - Flip him over.
来 让他躺一下
Let him lie down.
要不要去医院
Get him to the hospital.
可能是吃太快了
Perhaps he ate too quickly.
他没事吗
Is he okay?
-没事 -你干什么
He's fine.
去医院
Hospital.
Hospital. let's go to the hospital.
关门
Close the door.
你刚才药下太多了
You put too much in his food.
我
Me?
-就跟平常一样啊 -他多大
- It was the same as always. - He's a kid.
小孩要那么多份量吗
Kids don't require such a big dose.
刚才尊者治疗的时候你在乱什么
Why did you interrupt His Holiness?
这小孩子出事你给我负全责
You're responsible if anything happens to this kid.
回去
Get out.
你儿子现在
Your son
肺部感染了
has a chest infection.
你看这个阴影的部分
You can see this shadow here.
这有可能是肺积水
It might be pulmonary edema.
然后这些白白的地方有没有
And you see these white areas?
这可能是感染或是气胸
It may be an infection or pneumothorax.
怎么会这样
How is that possible?
他本来还好好的
He was perfectly fine before.
你儿子过往
Does your son
有没有什么慢性疾病史
have any history of chronic illness?
没有 他一直身体都很好
No, he's always been in good health.
只是脑子有点不灵活
He's just not very sharp.
为什么会突然变这样
How could this happen all of a sudden?
真的很奇怪
It's very strange.
这种状况不可能是一天两天造成的
This isn't something that develops in a few days.
尊者
Your Holiness.
尊者大慈大悲
Please have mercy.
求你救救我儿子 求求你
Please save my son. I beg you.
他刚才腹吐黑水
He just vomited black water.
应该是体内有不干净的东西
There's probably something unclean inside him.
我来帮你们解决
I'll take care of it for you.
绝对不能让他死
Don't let him die.
是
Okay.
也绝对不能让他好
But don't let him recover either.
我希望他永远保持这样
I want to keep him like this forever.
能做到吗
Can you do that?
这是我特地帮你做的
I made this especially for you.
来 这边坐
Please sit.
现在把存折跟印章放在里面
Now put your passbook and stamp inside.
提款卡呢
And your debit card?
这些都是虚荣之物
These are all vanity possessions.
还有你手上的戒指
And the ring on your finger.
这是结婚戒指
This is my wedding ring.
我什么都没有了
I don't have anything left.
只剩下这个
This is all I have.
你现在是在为你儿子
You are doing this for your son.
就是你这种执迷
It's this kind of obsession
才害你先生早早往生
that led to your husband's premature death.
你现在再不悔改
If you don't repent now,
下一个受害的就是你儿子了
the next victim will be your son.
先回去准备吧
Go get ready first.
谢谢尊者
Thank you, Your Holiness.
接着我说一句
Every time I say a line,
你跟着我说一句
you repeat after me.
我感谢天地
I thank heaven and earth.
I thank heaven and earth!
我感谢父母
I thank my parents.
I thank my parents!
我是罪人
I'm a sinner.
I'm a sinner!
我危害人间
I have harmed the world.
I have harmed the world!
我辜负苍生
I let the world down.
I let the world down!
把东西收好
Pack your things.
把儿子接走
Go get your son.
他们帮不到你
They can't help you.
-走开 -拿走
- Get lost. - Take it.
拿走
Take it.
把儿子接走
Get your son out of here!
接走
Go get him!
带你儿子
Get your son!
乱你心者 必为魔障
Demonic forces are messing with your mind.
慈悲用错地方
Compassion in the wrong place
只会伤害自己
will only hurt yourself.
走啊
Go!
走
Go.
走啊
Go!
你心慈手软 一拖再拖
Your compassion and indecision
最后只会酿成大祸
will only lead to catastrophe!
杀
Kill!
走
Go.
杀
Kill!
走啊
Go!
杀
Kill!
满身业障 危害人间
Full of karmic obstacles. A harm to the world.
一起送进地狱
Send them to hell together.
♪ 你看 它白色的翅膀 ♪
♪ Look at his white wings ♪
♪ 耀眼而无暇 ♪
♪ Dazzling and flawless ♪
♪ 我们 平凡的灵魂 ♪
♪ Our ordinary souls ♪
♪ 紧紧跟随不需多想 ♪
♪ Follow closely and shall not fall behind ♪
♪ 生命这样的旅程 ♪
♪ This journey of life ♪
♪ 我渴求你的微笑来完整 ♪
♪ Is completed by my yearning and your smile ♪
♪ 你能为我打开自由的门 ♪
♪ You can open my door to freedom ♪
♪ 牵起手吧 牵起手吧 ♪
♪ -Hold my hand -Hold my hand ♪
♪ 新造的人 新造的人 ♪
♪ -Brand new person -Brand new person ♪
（杨淑珍母子）
我要送你一个礼物
I have a gift for you.
你猜会是男的还是女的
Do you think it's a boy or girl?
我一天到晚说我得癌症
I keep saying I have cancer every day.
还好
Luckily,
还好这些都不是真的
none of it is true.
我曾经是一个子宫颈癌末期的患者
I was once a terminal cervical cancer patient.
在那段日子里
During that time,
每天都像是在倒数一样
every day was like a countdown.
我非常地感谢尊者
I'm very thankful to His Holiness
谢谢他愿意为我开悟
for being willing to enlighten me.
爱
Love
是上天赐给我们最好的礼物
is God's greatest gift to us.
我们都忘记了自己才是最好的人
We've all forgotten that we are the best people.
林禄和
Lin Lu-ho.
绰号牛头
Nickname, "Bullhead".
犯下五十多起枪击案
Committed more than 50 shootings.
杀了六个警察
Killed six police officers.
这你啊
That's you.
一场天灾
A natural disaster
一次地震
or an earthquake
就死多少无辜的人
can kill countless innocent people.
你恨过天吗
Do you hate the heavens?
恨过地吗
Do you hate the earth?
我们只不过多杀几个人
All we do is kill a few more people.
那又怎么样呢
What's the big deal?
是不是
Right?
死到临头还嘴硬啊
Talking tough even when you're about to die.
你果然该死
You truly deserve to die.
我跟关圣帝君请示过
I asked for a sign from Holy Emperor Guan.
当天祂给我九个圣杯
That day, he gave me nine divination sticks.
如果我枪里接下来九发子弹都卡弹
If the next nine bullets in my gun jam,
我走
I'll leave.
如果没有那就是天意
If not, then it's God's will.
那就是上天惩罚你玩弄苍生
It's God punishing you for playing with people's lives.
♪ 曾经 我茫然前行 ♪
♪ I once wandered aimlessly ♪
♪ 黯夜的路上 ♪
♪ On the dark night road ♪
♪ 微风 刺痛着灵魂 ♪
♪ The gentle breeze pricks my soul ♪
♪ 找不到应该的方向 ♪
♪ Unable to find the right direction ♪
我给大家一分钟的时间
I'll give everybody one minute.
选择留下来的人
Those who choose to stay
结果就跟他一样
will end up like him.
♪ 生命这样的旅程 ♪
♪ The journey of life ♪
♪ 要用多少泪水来完整 ♪
♪ Requires how many tears to complete? ♪
时间差不多啰
Time is almost up.
十
Ten,
九
nine,
八
eight,
七
seven,
六
six,
五
five,
四
four,
三
three,
二
two,
一
one.
♪ 我们 平凡的灵魂 ♪
♪ Our ordinary souls ♪
♪ 紧紧跟随不需多想 ♪
♪ Follow closely and shall not fall behind ♪
喂
Hey.
我已经在船上了
I'm already on the boat.
你不陪我一起搭
You should've come with me.
要四个小时耶
It's a four-hour ride.
那你等下要接我喔
You have to pick me up later.
外面还是很漂亮
It's so pretty outside.
跟你借一下
Let me borrow your phone.
不好意思
Sorry.
你朋友先不跟你说啰 不好意思
Your friend can't talk right now. Sorry about that.
陈灰
Chen Hui.
你们不要过来
Don't come any closer!
陈灰
Chen Hui!
谢谢 辛苦了
Thanks for your help.
陈桂林 看这边
Chen Kui-lin, over here!
你后悔吗
Do you regret it?
我叫陈桂林
My name is Chen Kui-lin!
陈桂林
Chen Kui-lin!
进去
Get in.
好 进去
Okay, get in.
日前发生在台中的黑道仇杀案
The gangster murder case in Taichung
终于有了最新发展
finally has a new development.
除了杀害枪击要犯香港仔之外
After killing the fugitive Hongkie,
陈桂林今天再度犯案
Chen Kui-lin has struck again today.
案发地点在澎湖
The crime took place in Penghu,
澎十四乡的一所灵修中心
at a spiritual center in Huxi Township.
你怎么变成这样了
What happened to you?
现在每天都是你的新闻
You're on the news every day.
你一定很开心喔
You must be happy.
我进来以后做了一次体检
I had a health check when I arrived here.
这里的医生告诉我
The doctor told me
我没有得过肺癌
I never had lung cancer.
这几天我就在想
I started thinking these last few days.
这世界上是不是有神迹啊
Could it really be a miracle?
到底是不是林禄和救了我
Did Lin Lu-ho really heal me?
如果你是得了肺癌突然好起来
If you had lung cancer and suddenly recovered,
那是神迹
then that's a miracle.
但要是你根本就没事
But if you never even had it,
那只是迷信
it's just superstition.
所以一开始那张X光片
So that X-ray
不是我的
wasn't mine.
那双肺是我的
That was my lung.
你为什么
Why?
我去医院拿报告那天
The day I got the report at the hospital,
我大学同学跟我说
my college classmate told me,
贵卿 你也是个医生
"Kuei-ching, you're a doctor too."
我突然觉得好羞愧
I suddenly felt so ashamed.
这些年我到底都在干嘛
What have I been doing all these years?
都在为你们道上的弟兄
Helping all you gangsters
拔子弹
extract bullets,
缝刀伤
stitch up knife wounds.
我到底是在救人还是在害人
Was I saving people or harming people?
本来我也只是想替自己积点阴德
I initially wanted to accumulate some good deeds
骗你去自首
by tricking you to turn yourself in.
从来没想过事情会变成现在这个样子
I never thought it would turn out like this.
但后来想一想
But come to think of it,
这也算一举三得吧
I did kill three birds with one stone.
我积到了阴德
I accumulated my good deeds,
你成了大人物
you became infamous,
社会从此又少了三个罪犯
and society has three less criminals.
这不是很好吗
Isn't that a good thing?
幸好我上了你的当
I'm glad I fell for it.
这个也许就是
Perhaps,
这个世界上最有价值的谎言
it was the world's most useful lie.
这个不行
Not this.
这个也不行
Not this either.
这两个不行
Not these two.
-都没了 -没了
- Is that all? - That's everything.
按规定这些都不行
These are all banned under the rules.
典狱长
Warden.
你看一下这个
Take a look at this.
这个自己用的
This is mine.
又旧又钝 完全没有杀伤力
It's old, blunt and harmless.
通融一下
Please allow it.
再见
Goodbye.
这个是陈桂林要我交给你的
Chen Kui-lin asked me to give you this.
（程小美）
现在跟你核对一下身份
We will now verify your identity.
受刑人姓名 陈桂林
Prisoner name Chen Kui-lin.
身份证字号 A125783729
ID number A125783729.
出生年月日 民国75年
Born 1986,
5月21号生
May 21.
请问以上是否正确
Is the above correct?
是
Yes.
请问你还有什么遗言想要交代的
Do you have any last words
或者是其他需要
or any other requests to
想要转达给你的亲友
pass on to friends or relatives?
我对不起大家
I'm sorry to everyone.
对不起社会
I'm sorry to society.
对不起
Sorry.
请在这边签个名
Please sign here.
（陈桂林）
谢谢
Thank you.
请问你有需要打麻醉吗
Would you like an anesthetic?
不用了 谢谢
No, thank you.